

Yinghe Liu

🧕 136 Abermuir Hts, State College, PA 🔑 <u>8144418656</u> 👲 <u>yingheliu@outlook.com</u>

Summary

Originating from central China, Liu pursued an undergraduate degree in psychology, focusing on cognitive and developmental perspectives. At Penn State, he contributed to research by collecting Electrodermal Activity data in parentchild interaction studies and creating a data-sharing handbook for a developmental psychology platform named DataBrary. He is now preparing to apply for a PhD program to further advance his skills and expertise in the field.

Education

Pennsylvania State University, University Park

Psychology

GPA: 3.81/4.00 Bachelor of Science

August 2021 to May 2024

Curriculum Highlights: Basic Methods in Psychological Study, Elementary Statistics, Cognitive Development, Cognitive Neuroscience, Physiological Psychology, Problems in Childhood/Adolescence

Experience

Brain and Behavioral Dynamics Lab

Undergraduate Research Assistance

State College, PA

August 2023 to May 2024

- Secure sharing of personal data and technologies.
- Create a guidebook for Databrary by using R language.
- Supervisor: Rick Gilmore, PhD; Andrea Seisler, MS.
- https://gilmore-lab.github.io

Parent-Child Dynamic Lab

Undergraduate Research Assistance State College, PA

May 2023 to May 2024

- Understand how parents regulate themselves while disciplining their children.
- Assess physiological reaction during the Parent-Child Dynamic Test (PCCT) and the Trier Social Stress Test (TSST).
- Collect and ensure the quality of Electrodermal Activity Data (Skin Conductance). Supervisor: Erika Lunkenheimer, PhD.
- https://pcd.la.psu.edu/meet-the-team/
- Pennsylvania State University

Undergraduate Teaching Assistance

State College, PA August 2023 to May 2024

• PSYCH413 Cognitive Development: an advanced undergraduate course covering the following topics: Biological

- basis, Perception, Language, Executive functions, etc. Coordinate grading and develop quizzes, exams, and homework.
- Supervisor: Rodrigo Cardenas, PhD.

Projects

DataBrary Guide A complete user guide to the Databrary system built in Quarto.

August 2023 - May 2024

Databrary is a useful data management and storage system dedicating to developmental science. Available at: https://nyu. databrary.org.

https://github.com/databrary/guide

Skills

MindWare Packages

Psychophysiology Assessment Tool

Stress Assessment, Heart Rate, Skin Conductance

Merged platform of R and Python Microsoft 365

Elementary Usage of Word, Excel, Teams

Languages

Proficient

Native

English

Ouarto

Chinese

Professor of Psychology, Pennsylvania State University

References

114 Moore Building

Rick O. Gilmore

University Park, PA 16802

rog1@psu.edu (814) 865-3664

Previous lab supervisor

Erika Lunkenheimer

https://rick-gilmore.com

Professor of Psychology, Pennsylvania State University 140 Moore Building

University Park, PA 16802

ezl5238@psu.edu

(814) 863-7002

Previous lab supervisor

https://prevention.psu.edu/person/erika-lunkenheimer/

Rodrigo Cardenas

Associate Teaching Professor of Psychology

137 Moore Building

University Park, PA 16802

ac35@psu.edu

(814) 865-7679

Former teaching supervisor

https://psych.la.psu.edu/people/rac35/